<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: arduino | Han Qin . Me]]></title>
  <link href="http://hanqin.me/blog/categories/arduino/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://hanqin.me/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-23T23:46:20+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://hanqin.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Han Qin]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ardroid environment sensor - my first android - arduino project]]></title>
    <link href="http://hanqin.me/blog/2013/10/23/ardroid-environment-sensor-my-first-android-arduino-project/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-23T22:37:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://hanqin.me/blog/2013/10/23/ardroid-environment-sensor-my-first-android-arduino-project</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, I have spent most of my spare time on <a href="http://www.arduino.cc/">arduino</a>, an open-source
electronics prototyping platform.</p>

<p>Arduino is very easy to use that one with little hardware
knowledge like me could start making something quickly, and with various shields
and sensors, it is also very powerful.</p>

<p>Ok, let&rsquo;s go to the main topic today, my first android arduino project.</p>

<p>The reason for the small project is very tricky, that is, I usually doubt the
weather and envrionmental info from official departments, especially for the PM
2.5, As a result I decided to build an environment sensor and take it with me
every day. The data around me is the most accurate one, right?</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/ardroid.png" title="&lsquo;image&rsquo; &lsquo;images&rsquo;" >
Above is how ardorid looks like, at the time of writing, I havn&rsquo;t found
a satisfying PM2.5 sensor, so you can only see two lines showing.</p>

<h4>The basic idea is:</h4>

<ol>
<li><p>android device (my Huawei Y300) will act as a collector, analyser and display
of the envriomental data.</p></li>
<li><p>arduino(openjumper mega2560, openjumper sensor shield v3, bluetooth adapter,
dht11 sensor) will retrieve data and feed to the collector.</p></li>
</ol>


<h4>Some details of the tech stack:</h4>

<ol>
<li><p>For the beautiful dynamic chart, the framework is <em>AChartEngine</em>.</p></li>
<li><p>For communication between android and arduino, <em>Firmata</em> is your friend.</p></li>
<li><p>Also, <em>bluetooth</em> is a nice choice besides google ADK board.
<em>OpenJumper sensor shield v3</em> makes the integration of bluetooth module, <em>DHT11</em> sensor supper easy.</p></li>
<li>Others like the battery-powersource, gradle will lead you a good life:)</li>
</ol>


<p>Please refer to <a href="https://github.com/hanqin/Ardroid">Github</a> for the code.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
